A Guide to the Mary Ellen Harryman Ruffner Papers, 1795-1976 (bulk 1855-1930)
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Photographs, ca. 1850-1976 (bulk 1880-1920)., Extent: 2 reels of microfilm. (Reels Misc. reels 5144-5145)
  This series includes photographs, ca. 1850-1976 (bulk 1880-1920), of the Clark, Gaunt, Harryman, Klipstein, Morrison, Ruffner, and Taylor families. A number of the photographs, ca. 1850-1900, were taken in studios in Alexandria, Lynchburg, and Richmond, Virginia; and Baltimore, Maryland; St. Louis, Missouri; and Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Included are images depicting social gatherings, family, church, and school events, vacations, parks, and houses.Of note is an album from Rebecca Taylor Klipstein's automobile trip to California, 1920, from Alexandria, Virginia. Also included are numerous photographs of the Ruffner family, including Richard Laidley Ruffner I, in soldier's uniform World War I, with family, friends, vacations in Europe, and electrical breakers and transformers, possibly in West Virginia, ca. 1895-1960. Also included are photographs of Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, family and school life, and with his sister, Rebecca Mary Ruffner. The collection also includes a number of daugerrotypes.
  Arranged alphabetically by family name with unidenitified photographs arranged to the rear.
  - Charles Taylor I Clark and Katherine Gilmore Clark family, ca. 1850-1920.
  - Frances Ann Clark, ca. 1870-1880.
  - Elizabeth Forsythe Gaunt, ca. 1890.
  - Martha Lloyd Gaunt, ca. 1860-1870.
  - Samuel Gaunt, ca. 1890.
  - Gaunt family, ca. 1860.
  - Harry Gaunt Harryman, ca. 1890-1910.
  - Mary Theresa Klipstein Harryman, ca. 1860-1930.
  - Harry and Mary Harryman family, ca. 1900-1930.
  - William Klipstein Harryman, I, ca. 1890-1910.
  - Harryman family, ca. 1880-1920.
  - George Taylor Klipstein, ca. 1860-1929.
  - James Klipstein, ca. 1890.
  - Louise and William Klipstein, ca. 1890.
  - Mary Klipstein, ca. 1880.
  - Mary Ann Taylor Klipstein, ca. 1850-1900.
  - Naomi Simmons Klipstein, ca. 1900.
  - Rebecca Taylor Klipstein, Trip to California, ca. 1920.
  - Rebecca Taylor Klipstein, ca. 1860-1930.
  - Rosaline Klipstein, ca. 1880.
  - William Ball Klipstein, ca. 1880-1920.
  - Klipstein family, ca. 1880-1920.
  - Millier family, ca. 1880-1920.
  - Mary E.R. Moffett, ca. 1860-1900.
  - Morrison family, ca. 1860-1900.
  - Mrs. I. F. Rodes, ca. 1880.
  - Mrs. Ross, ca. 1880.
  - David Lewis Ruffner, II, ca. 1877.
  - David Lewis Ruffner, III, ca. 1896-1945.
  - Lady Diane Ruffner, ca. 1900.
  - Dorcas Blaine and Joel Henry Ruffner, ca. 1890.
  - Mary Ellen Harryman Ruffner, ca. 1893-1910.
  - Mary Ellen Harryman Ruffner, ca. 1920-1964.
  - Percy Laidley Ruffner, I, ca. 1940.
  - Rebecca Mary Ruffner, ca. 1930.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, I, 1894-1965.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, I, ca. 1920-1930.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, I, ca. 1920-1930.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, ca. 1930-1960.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, ca. 1930-1965.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, ca. 1950-1976.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, Travel ca. 1950-1960.
  - Rebecca Mary and Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, ca. 1931-1934.
  - Rebecca Mary and Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, Album, ca. 1931-1934.
  - Rebecca Mary and Richard Laidley Ruffner, II, ca. 1931-1934.
  - Richard Laidley Ruffner, III, ca. 1960.
  - Ruffner family, ca. 1930-1960.
  - Frances E. Smoot, ca. 1898.
  - Adolfe Charles Taylor, ca. 1880-1900.
  - Charles Marll Taylor, ca. 1870.
  - Esther Taylor, ca. 1870.
  - George Richards Taylor, ca. 1870.
  - George Richards Taylor, II, ca. 1880-1900.
  - Katherine Smoot Taylor, ca. 1870.
  - Louise K. Taylor, ca. 1880-1900.
  - Mary Ann Taylor, ca. 1870.
  - Rebecca Marll Taylor, ca. 1880-1900.
  - Theresa Louise de Paul Taylor, ca. 1880-1900.
  - Walter Cerre Taylor, ca. 1870-1880.
  - Taylor family, ca. 1880-1900.
  - Unidentified, ca. 1870-1910.
  - Unidentified, ca. 1920-1940.
  - Unidentified, ca. 1950-1960.
  - Unidentified, ca. 1950.
  - Unidentified, Travel.
  - Unidentified, Travel.
  - Unidentified, Travel.
  - Unidentified, Houses.